[music]
>> Hello everyone and welcome to this
Business Central Launch Edition session
on the cloud migration tooling. My name
is Joost. I'm the product owner for the
cloud migration tooling and today I'm
joined by my colleague Yeah, I'm Wenjie.
I'm the software engineer working on the
cloud migration.
All right. So today we're here to
present three new
features for the cloud migration tooling
that we've worked on for the past year.
We've made some some significant changes
to the cloud migration platform that now
make it easier to migrate from different
sources or with different tables.
So today we'll present how you can
create your own migration tool in your
own app.
How you can
re-implement from Business Central
version 14 for customers that are stuck
on older on-premise versions.
And finally we'll show you how to do a
migration setup without any code.
Firstly, we've launched the ability for
developers to create their own migration
tooling. Meaning that
Business Central developer can write an
app that defines the table mappings and
setup data
to migrate to Business Central from any
SQL based source using the existing
migration tooling.
Now to show you how it works, Wenjie.
Thanks.
Thanks Joost.
I will introduce how to implement your
own cloud migration tool. It's quite
simple. There are only two things.
First, you need to provide your table
mappings.
There are two kind of table mappings.
One is replication table mappings. It is
defined to
sorry, it defines which table will be
moved to Business Central.
Another one is setup table mappings.
It's similar but it will be replicated
once connected to the on-premise
database. So it can be used during the
setup
step
Second, you need to remember to create a
new table with company information in
the source database. The table can be
named as company or anything else you
want but it must contain two fields. One
is name, another one is display name.
The table must be created with a SQL
script.
For extensibility
we created a new interface called
customer migration provider to make it
simpler to integrate.
After implementing this interface,
you must extend the enum to make your
cloud migration tool visible in our
standard wizard page.
So just like ISVs can now build their
own apps to migrate from any SQL based
source. Within the Business Central
team, we've developed our first custom
migration tool ourselves.
This is the Business Central version 14
re-implementation tool which enables
customers that are stuck on older
on-premise versions
to migrate to Business Central
with only their core business data. This
tool lets you move only a subset of your
of the data and it replaces the process
that some partners are going through
with customers to migrate this data
using configuration packages.
So this tool is good for customers that
are stuck on older Business Central and
NAV on-premise versions and it moves
only a subset of their data.
So some partners over the past years
have migrated these customers using
configuration packages giving them a
clean start in SaaS.
But now using this tool, there's no need
to use these configuration packages
anymore. You can simply set this up,
migrate the master data, select the
transactional data opening balances and
the essential setup data from the
on-premise environment to get started in
SaaS.
This is useful for customers that are
looking for this fresh start and I can
update their business processes to be
more standardized in Business Central
and leverage more of our AI and genetic
features in the cloud.
Yeah.
Then I will show how to use the
the BC14 re-implementation tool in
Business Central.
First, we need to go to the
cloud migration management page and then
open the wizard page.
Yeah, here you can see because we extend
the enum, so we there is a new option
called Business Central 14
re-implementation
option here. So let's select this.
Then next, we need to fill some SQL
connection string.
Yeah.
Once we connected to the on-premise
database, we can find all the available
companies.
You can select one of them or you can
also select all.
Then we need to move to cloud migration
management page.
Once we complete the setup at the very
beginning, you can see the status it's
it's waiting for
creating companies. We need to wait for
it.
Yeah.
Then
once the creating complete
we can start to run the replication.
Now it's
it's in progress.
It could take several minutes.
Then here you can see the replication
progress it's completed
successfully.
Then the status is changed to upgrade in
progress.
This is because by default the upgrade
the upgrade will be triggered
automatically after migration. But if
you don't want that, you can also change
it in the setting page.
Yeah, then we need to wait for the
complete of upgrade.
And you can also find some details of
the migration for every tables.
And you can also find how many lines
it's successfully migrated.
Then just to wait for several minutes
and the
upgrade progress will complete. Yeah,
now it's completed.
So as you're getting ready to migrate
your older customers on version 14,
there's a few things that are good to
know.
Firstly, we only support this tool for
migrations from Business Central version
14. So no older or later versions than
that.
We intend to make this tool open source
meaning that you can find the source
code on GitHub. You can contribute to it
to add or remove tables to migrate
or you can extend it to also migrate
tables from your ISV solutions.
This is built as a custom cloud
migration tool. So it's built on the
same platform that Wenjie just showed to
migrate from any SQL based source and
you can review the source code, learn
from it and then build similar tools to
migrate from other sources.
And finally it's good to mention that
this is still work in progress. We're
expecting to ship it in one of the first
minor updates of version 28.
Finally, we've also built the ability to
migrate from any SQL source without
writing any code with these new platform
changes.
To do this, you can define custom table
mappings in the cloud migration setup
and migrate individual tables from your
SQL source.
This is useful if you're migrating
individual tables ad hoc.
For example, if you're missing
individual tables after completing the
initial migration or if you want to do
performance testing using real data. So
you can imagine migrating some large
tables that could be a concern for
performance for prospective customer in
the cloud
to a sandbox environment and then test
the performance of that environment
using real data.
This
no-code data migration from any SQL
source is highly controlled. So you
select the tables that you want to be
copied and nothing else will be copied.
And finally, it's good to mention that
system tables that are inaccessible by
AL code can still not be migrated using
this tool. So this has not been possible
by other migration tools built on top of
our cloud migration platform and it's
not possible with this one either. So
there's no changes there.
Now to show you how this work, back to
Wenjie.
I will show you how to use the non-code
migration in Business Central.
First, the same. We need to go to the
cloud migration management page to
enable the custom migration.
Then once it's enabled, we need to add
some new table mappings.
Yeah.
Here we just select the tenant media
table
as an example.
Adding the map.
Yeah, then we also add another map for
the tenant media set table.
Now we successfully added two
table mappings and in this page we can
find we also support the import and
export. So you don't need to configure
it every time. You can export your
configuration and then import it in a
new tenant.
Then once we complete the the mappings
we can
we need to
start the wizard page.
And here we need to
select the custom migration.
Then the same as before, we need to fill
some SQL connection strings
to connect to the on-premise database.
Then select companies.
Yeah, finally run the replication. And
then it will automatically trigger the
upgrade progress.
Here you can see it's completed.
Then we can check how many tables are
migrated.
That concludes our session on cloud
migration as part of the Business
Central Launch Edition.
Thank you for watching and let us know
what you think on Viva Engage. Wenjie,
myself and other engineers working on
these tools are actively engaging with
partners there to hear your scenarios,
get your feedback, answer your questions
and get your ideas on how to improve
this further.
Thank you. Thank you.